BORN: May 7, 1997 **EMAIL**: ruamberg@icloud.com ruamberg.github.io

Developer

About me

WHOIAM

Ruamberg Aguiar, 21, Automation and Control Engineering undergraduate student at POLI / UPE (Polytechnic School of Pernambuco/University of Pernambuco - Brazil), which works with IoT and embedded systems development. Started in 2011 building projects to robotic championships and hackathons around the world. At college, leadered a robotic team for two years where started science skills searching biosignals and computing processing on them. Nowadays, have been working with IoT systems and software development. My aim is to use my abilities with the mechatronic engineering world, programming and design to rise a new culture based on the devices we build.

Language Skills

ENGLISH

Accurate english speaking (B2) and advanced knowledge with writing and reading.

Language) Intermediate level

LIBRAS (Brazilian Sign

interpreter.

GERMAN

Basic skills(A1).

C/C++

ELETRONICS AND CIRCUITS

Development Skills

manufacturing PCB's and soldering all kinds of discrete and SMD components.

Development of circuits using the Proteus software,

Large experience with developing embedded software for open source platforms like Arduino and

ESP. Using advanced resources of organizations and protocols in the sketch. WEB DESIGN & NODE.JS

Skills on develop and edit HTML CSS JS websites and

basic Node.js applications (Express, React Native, Electron, etc.).

and Experiences

Work

APRIL 2017 - PRESENT

DEVELOPER

L2 TECNOLOGIA

IoT and embedded systems developer.

RESEARCHER

2016

Electromyo sensors development and data science.

POLI / UNIVERSITY OF PERNAMBUCO

ROBOTIC TEAM DEVELOPER POLI/UNIVERSITY OF PERNAMBUCO

2014 and 2015

ENGLISH TEACHER

COMPASSION INTERNATIONAL

2015

Education

ACADEMIC CAREER

GRADUATING POLI / UNIVERSITY OF PERNAMBUCO

Undergraduate degree on

Automation and Control Engineering.

2014 - NOW

ENGLISH COURSE

SENAC

2012 - 2014

Advenced english course completed.

GERMAN COURSE

CCBA - German/Brazilian Cultural

language by Babel classes.

Center 2017

Al.1 semester of german classes at CCBA, after this, started studying the